Guide to the Jeanne Audrey Powers Papers RL.10181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Files, 1959-2011 and undated
  - Ecumenical and Interreligious Work
    - Church Study Guides - 1978-1997 (Box 37)
    - Consultation on Church Union - 1976-2001 (Box 37)
    - Ecumenical - 1986 (Box 37)
    - The Ecumenical Decade (1 of 2) - 1975-1992 (Box 37)
    - The Ecumenical Decade (2 of 2) - 1987-1992 (Box 38)
    - The Ecumenical Decade: Women (1 of 2) - 1992-1994 (Box 38)
    - The Ecumenical Decade: Women (2 of 2) - 1988-1998 (Box 38)
    - Ecumenism - 1960-1994 (Box 38)
    - Encuentro '89: World Conference on Mission Evangelism (Box 38)
    - Faith Order - 1973 (Box 38)
    - New Hymns/Liturgy/New Services/Chas Wesley - 1968-2003 (Box 38)
    - Suffrage Ordination - 1970-2002 (Box 38)
    - Theology - 1960-2000 (Box 39)
    - Worship Poetry - 1980-1992 (Box 39)
    - Worship Services - 1974-1999 (Box 39)
    - Ecumenical Institute - 1961-1968 (Box 34)
    - Union Seminary Polity Course - Undated (Box 94)
    - Garrett Evangelical T.S. Trusteeship - 1995-1997 (Box 94)
    - G-ETS Academic Affairs Committee (Trustees) - 1999-2000 (Box 94)
    - Seminary Study at St. Andrew's - 1934-2010 (Box 94)
    - Continuing Ed - 1967-1976 (Box 94)
    - RS-I PED - Undated (Box 94)
    - Cornet - 1999-2008 (Box 94)
  - Professional Correspondence and Writing
    This subseries contains Powers' professional correspondence and writing. This includes individual correspondence, speaking engagements, and materials related to her retirement. Also included are materials documenting Powers' coming out in 1995.
    - Vocational Correspondence - 1956-1961 (Box 47)
    - Annual Salary With Correspondence - 1958-1963 (Box 48)
    - Recommendations - 1964-1994 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Informational Articles - 1967-1987 (Box 43)
    - Send-off to NYC - 1968 (Box 49)
    - JAP Writings and Articles - Pre-1970s (Box 42)
    - JAP Writings and Articles - 1970s (4 folders) (Box 42)
    - Speaking Invitations: Declined - 1971-1973 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence: Others - 1971-1983 (Box 44)
    - Acceptances: Completed - 1972-1986 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence: Task Force Members - 1973-1982 (Box 44)
    - Speaking Invitations: Declined - 1974-1976 (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondences Regarding 'Rituals in a New Day,' etc. - 1976-1979 (3 folders) (Box 45)
    - Speaking Invitations: Declined - 1977-1980 (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - English Correspondence - 1977-1978 (Box 43)
    - Speaking Invitations: Declined - 1979 (Box 44)
    - Form Letter JAP: Positive - 1981 (Box 40)
    - JAP Writings and Articles - 1990s (Box 41)
    - Form Letter From JAP - ca. 1980s (Box 40)
    - Personal Responses From JAP: Positive - ca. 1980s (Box 40)
    - Speaking Invitations: Declined - 1981-1991 (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Correspondence - 1981-1986 (Box 44)
    - Conflict w/ Gen. Sec. - 1987-1990 (Box 48)
    - JAP Writings and Articles - 1990s (Box 40)
    - JA Powers Sabbatical Report - 1995 (Box 48)
    - Chrono - 1995-1996 (Box 43)
    - Religious Press (re JA Powers Coming Out) - 1995-1996 (Box 47)
    - Secular Press (re JA Powers Coming Out) - 1995-1996 (Box 47)
    - JAP Retirement: MN - 1996 (Box 45)
    - Personal Responses From JAP: Negative - Undated (Box 40)
    - JA Powers - 1950s (Box 45)
    - JA Powers: Writings - 1960-1961 (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - JA Powers: Writings - 1962-1969 (8 folders) (Box 46)
    - Ja Powers: Writings - 1970s (Box 46)
    - JA Powers: Writings - 1980-1994 (14 folders) (Box 46)
    - Writings: JA Powers - 1995-2006 (11 folders) (Box 47)
    - Three Sets of JA Powers' Coming Out Packet - 1995 (Box 47)
    - Coming Out Speech Preparation - 1993-2000 (Box 47)
    - Core Resources/Reflections for JA Powers' Coming Out Speech - 1986-1995 (Box 47)
    - Responses: Positive - 1995-1996 (Box 47)
    - Response: Positive: Work-Related - 1995 (Box 47)
    - Responses: Negative - 1995-1996 (Box 48)
    - Post Coming Out: IRD Campaign vs. JA Powers GCCUIC Position: Correspondence - 1990-1996 (Box 48)
    - IRD Campaign Against JA Powers GCCUIC Position: Press - 1995-1996 (Box 48)
    - Coming Out: Press - 1995-2000 (Box 48)
    - Annual Work Reports (NYC) - 1968-1996 (Box 48)
    - Articles/Sermons: JAP Wants to Save - 1965-2008 (Box 49)
    - Press re JA Powers - 1973-2007 (Box 49)
    - JA Powers on The Phil Donahue Show - 1981 (Box 49)
    - Appreciations - 1995-2011 (Box 49)
    - Retirement: Daytona Beach: GCCUIC - 1991-1995 (Box 49)
    - Misc Events, Conference, Workshops - 2001-2009 (Box 49)
    - Honoring Friends - 1990-2004 (Box 49)
    - Interviews w/ JA Powers - 1991 (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous Press re: JA Powers - 1976-1991 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, Professional - Undated (Box 95)
    - JA Powers Correspondence - 1984-1999 (Box 95)
    - Correspondence, Misc - 2000-2011 (2 folders) (Box 95)
  - Activism
    Contains documents relating to Powers' work on issues such as racism, sexism, suicide, inclusivity, women in the church, clergywomen, feminism, AIDS, and LGBT issues in the United Methodist Church.
    - A Fixed Date for Easter - 1965 (Box 6)
    - WCC: 1st Assembly/Nairobi - 1975 (Box 56)
    - Divorce Responses: Zerox - 1977 (Box 54)
    - Achtemeier Controversy - 1978 (Box 54)
    - Marriage - 1978 (Box 54)
    - Commission on the Status and Role of Women: UMC (Madison, WI) - 1979 (Box 56)
    - Language Controversy: Inclusive Language Lectionary (Nat'l Council of Churches: 1981) - 1981 (Box 62)
    - Her Voice, Our Voice: Women's Solstice - 1986 (Box 62)
    - Language Consultation - 1986 (Box 52)
    - JA Powers/June Goldman: 'Goddess' Controversy - 1986 (Box 52)
    - Women and Spirituality - 1987 (Box 63)
    - Suicide (Hastening Death) - 1987 (Box 63)
    - And God Loves Each One: A Resource for Dialogue About the Church and Homosexuality - 1988 (Box 51)
    - Here Is My Hand: A Study Guide for Persons, Groups, and Congregations to Study What it Means to be Reconciled with all God's Children - 1990 (Box 50)
    - Reconciling Commission GCCUIC - 1990 (Box 55)
    - When Christians Disagree: by Harvey Lois Seifert - 1991 (Box 55)
    - Judicial Council: GCCUIC Reconciling Commission - 1991 (Box 55)
    - Faithful Inquiry: Exploring Christian Responses to Homosexual Persons - 1992 (Box 51)
    - Week of Prayer for Christian Unity (A Sermon) - 1996 (Box 56)
    - Reconciling Ministries: Convo - 2009 (Box 64)
    - Christian Social Action: A Special Issue on Homosexuality: Statements on the War, p.4 - February 1991 (Box 50)
    - When Christians Disagree: By Harvey Lois Seifert - 1991 (Box 50)
    - Report of the Committee to Study Homosexuality to the General Council on Ministries of the United Methodist Church - August 1991 (Box 50)
    - History Ministerial Record of Women of the Minnesota Annual Conference, UMC, 1856-1977 - Undated (Box 66)
    - Interfaith/Leadership Info - 1966-2005 (Box 53)
    - Clergy Couples - 1972-1981 (Box 54)
    - Sexism-Racism - 1973-1978 (Box 63)
    - Alternate Rituals Proj. (Documents): Cultural Context of Worship: Task Force: Jeanne Audrey Powers - 1973-1980 (Box 54)
    - Divorce Reviews - 1973-1980 (Box 54)
    - Divorce - 1974-1984 (Box 54)
    - Church Unity - 1974-1987 (Box 54)
    - Articles on Women the Church - 1975-1988 (Box 53)
    - General Conference on Homosexuality - 1976-1980 (Box 55)
    - Clergy Divorces - 1977-1978 (Box 55)
    - Council on Christian Unity - 1977-1987 (Box 53)
    - Salary Equalization Movement (JA Powers) - 1978-1983 (Box 55)
    - Inclusive Language Lectionary: Correspondence/News Releases, Articles - 1981-1983 (Box 52)
    - Inclusive Language: Guidelines, Statements, Resources - 1981-1984 (Box 52)
    - The Methodist Federation for Social Action - 1981-1991 (Box 55)
    - RSAC (Racism, Sexism, Classism) - 1982-1993 (Box 67)
    - NCC Lectionary: JAP - 1983-1984 (Box 52)
    - Women in the Church Movement - 1983-1987 (Box 54)
    - theOtherSide: Christians and Homosexuality: A discussion of biblical and ethical issues, plus a guide to 36 Christian organizations for gay and lesbian people - 1984 (Box 50)
    - NCCC Education TF/Inclusive Language - 1984-1985 (Box 52)
    - Reconciling Congregations - 1984-1990 (Box 55)
    - Homosexuality Task Force - 1988-1992 (Box 55)
    - Auburn Seminary Conferences [JAP]: 'Transforming Ecum.,' 'Sexuality/Spirituality,' 'Interfaith,' Women's - 1990, 1991, 1994 (Box 63)
    - Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women - 1990-1991 (Box 54)
    - Judicial Council 'Services of Union': Minn. - 1991-1993 (Box 55)
    - Judicial Council 'Services of Union': Troy, CA, OR, WVA - 1992-1993 (Box 55)
    - Judicial Council (Minn.) Legislation: Homosexuality - 1992-1995 (Box 55)
    - Judicial Council: Homosexuality Definition - 1993-1994 (Box 55)
    - Reconciling Board - 1995-2002 (Box 55)
    - GCCUIC - 1995-2008 (Box 57)
    - Biblical Translation - ca. 1980 (Box 52)
    - Language and Sexism - ca. 1980s (Box 52)
    - Women and Inclusivity - ca. 1980s (Box 52)
    - Unity and Evangelism - ca. 1980s (Box 52)
    - Homosexuality and Religion - ca. 1987 (Box 53)
    - MFSA Packet on Homosexuality - ca. 1989 (Box 51)
    - Inclusive Language - ca. 1990 (Box 52)
    - Workshop led by JAP: Churches in solidarity with women - ca. 1998 (Box 67)
    - Alternate Life Styles - Early 1970s (Box 58)
    - Hospitality, Healing, and Hope: National Convocation of Reconciling Congregations: Celebration of Worship - February 1990 (Box 50)
    - The Fourth National Convocation of Reconciling Congregations: Bound for the Promised Land: Augsburg College: Minneapolis, Minnesota - July 1995 (Box 50)
    - The Third National Convocation of Reconciling Congregations: Borne on the Breath of God: Remembering|Renewing|Reforming|Returning: George Washington University: Washington, DC - July 1993 (Box 50)
    - From Generation: Woman Church Speaks: Engeneracion - November 1983 (Box 50)
    - Commission on Christian Unity Interreligious Concerns - Pre-1995 (Box 57)
    - Open Hands: Journal of the Reconciling Congregation Program: Our Churches' Policies - Summer 1986 (Box 50)
    - Breaking the Silence Overcoming the Fear: Homophobia Education - Undated (Box 51)
    - Language - Undated (Box 51)
    - Bible Sexism - Undated (Box 51)
    - Inclusive Language Lectionary - 1983 (Box 52)
    - Language Consultation - 1986 (Box 52)
    - Inclusive Language Prime Resources - Undated (Box 56)
    - WCC - Undated (Box 56)
    - Inclusive Language - 1999-2006 (Box 56)
    - Jewish Inclusive Liturgy - Undated (Box 56)
    - Commission on Status Role of Women - 1976-2010 (Box 56)
    - COSROW Flyer Newsletters - 1980-2009 (Box 56)
    - GCCUIC - 1974-1996 (Box 57)
    - General Commission on Christian Unity Interreligious Concerns: Administrative - 1980-1994 (Box 57)
    - GCCUIC: CHARS Report - 1995 (Box 57)
    - GCCUIC: Ritual for a New Day - 1974 (Box 57)
    - UMC History, GLBT Issues - 1977-1990 (Box 57)
    - Cultural - Undated (Box 57)
    - Anglicans on Women/GLBT Issues - 1994-2006 (Box 58)
    - Christian-Jewish Dialogue - 1987-2007 (Box 58)
    - Christian Left - 1986-2006 (Box 58)
    - CLOUT - 1996-2005 (Box 58)
    - The 'Christian Right' - 1975-2009 (Box 58)
    - UM Christian Right Women - 1997-2002 (Box 58)
    - Clergy Conduct - 1995 (Box 58)
    - International Gaylesbian Human Rights Campaign (IGLHRC) - 1998 (Box 58)
    - More Light: Presbyterian GLBT Rights (Additional Lutheran Materials) - 1998-2001 (Box 58)
    - Racism - 2002 (Box 58)
    - Religious Groups Response to GLBT Issues - 1997-2001 (Box 58)
    - Sexism - Undated (Box 59)
    - Social Justice - 1997-2000 (Box 59)
    - Clergywomen, Bishops - 1998 (Box 59)
    - Clergywomen: Catholic - 1976-1995 (Box 59)
    - Clergywomen, General - 1979-1982 (Box 59)
    - Clergywomen: Methodist - 1984-2008 (Box 59)
    - Clergywomen: Protestant - 1980 (Box 59)
    - Feminism - 1970-2000 (Box 59)
    - Feminist Theologian's Writings - 1981-1997 (Box 59)
    - Theology, Feminist - 1979-2009 (Box 59)
    - Violence Toward Women - 1983-1996 (Box 59)
    - Womanist Theology - 1977-1984 (Box 59)
    - Women The Bible - 1991-1996 (Box 59)
    - Women Power - 1970-1987 (Box 60)
    - Women in History - 1978-1992 (Box 60)
    - Women Managing Wealth: Ms. Foundation - 1986-1991 (Box 60)
    - Women in Philanthropy Conference - 2000 (Box 60)
    - Women's Issues - 1995-2000 (Box 60)
    - Women's Music - 1984-1991 (Box 60)
    - Workshops on Women - 1982-1994 (Box 60)
    - AIDS Quilt Friends: Steve, Lyle Loder, Earl Brooks - 1987-1993 (Box 60)
    - Beginning of the UMC Homosexuality - 1974-1987 (Box 60)
    - Gay Christian Movement - 1979 (Box 60)
    - GLBT History - 1978-2006 (Box 60)
    - GLBT History: Madison Event - 1998-2002 (Box 60)
    - GLBT: History Project, Ecumenical Archives - 1975-2002 (Box 60)
    - Soulforce: GLBT History - 2001 (Box 61)
    - Heterosexism/Homophobia - 1978-1998 (Box 61)
    - Study Guide: Heterosexism - 1994 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/Bible - 1977-2000 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/Christianity - 1971-1999 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/Church - 1973-2001 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/Denominations - 1971-2000 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/UMC - 1998-2007 (Box 61)
    - Homosexuality/UMC History - 1975-1996 (Box 61)
    - Human Sexuality - 1964-1999 (Box 61)
    - Human Sexuality: Cal Pacific Conference - 1996-1999 (Box 61)
    - Human Sexuality/Lesbian Retreat Resources: W.A.T.E.R. - 1981-1997 (Box 61)
    - Marriage, Same Sex - 1973-2008 (Box 61)
    - Methodist History: GLBT Issues - 1975-2003 (Box 62)
    - Methodist History/GLBT Issues: Bishops - 1996-2000 (Box 62)
    - P-FLAG - Undated (Box 62)
    - Resources on GLBT - 1973-2000 (Box 62)
    - Sermons: GLBT - 1995-2009 (Box 62)
    - Trans-Gender - 1991-2010 (Box 62)
    - Hennepin Avenue UMC: Reconciling - 1993-2010 (Box 62)
    - Interfaith GLBT Info Study - 2004-2010 (Box 62)
    - Misc Clippings, Newsletters: Reconciling Resources, etc. - 1998-2009 (Box 62)
    - Parents' Reconciling Network - 2000-2008 (Box 63)
    - Reconciling Congregation Programs - 1996-2000 (Box 63)
    - Reconiling UM Resources - 1983-2005 (Box 64)
    - Reconciling Histories - 1999-2009 (Box 64)
    - Reconciling: U. Methodists - 1995-1996 (Box 64)
    - Reconciling Ministries Network - 1997-2010 (Box 64)
    - Reconciling Ministries: By-laws Policies - Undated (Box 64)
    - Reconciling Ministries: National Clergy - 2002-2009 (Box 64)
    - RMN Correspondence - 1997-2010 (Box 64)
    - RMN Correspondence: Internal - 2000-2002 (Box 64)
    - RMN Correspondence: External - 1998-2002 (Box 64)
    - RMN Histories Marriage - 1999-2008 (Box 65)
    - RMN: Minn - 2010-2011 (Box 65)
    - Minn RM Network Ministries - 1987-2010 (Box 65)
    - Reconciling Ministries National - 2009 (Box 65)
    - May '01 RMN Mtg.: Minneapolis! - 2000-2001 (Box 65)
    - Open House: RCP @ Jeanne Audrey Powers' (to meet RMN nat'l offices) - 1997 (Box 65)
    - Minn RRCC Conference (RRCC Newspaper) - 2006-2011 (Box 65)
    - RMN: Personnel Com - 1992-2001 (Box 65)
    - Reconciling Retired Clergy: The Beginnings - 2004-2010 (Box 65)
    - Reconciling Retired Clergy (Outside on MN) - 2005-2009 (Box 65)
    - Feminist Revolution - 1970-1980 (Box 66)
    - Feminist Theology - 1976-2009 (Box 66)
    - Human Sexuality the Church - 1973-2008 (Box 66)
    - Jewish/Christian - 1968 (Box 66)
    - Liberation Theology/International Diversity/Multiculturalism - 1977-1998 (Box 66)
    - Methodist Women's History - 1986-2003 (Box 66)
    - Women's Feminist Church: 1 of 2 - 1975-2010 (Box 67)
    - Women's Feminist Church: 2 of 2 - 1974-2008 (Box 67)
    - Women in the Church/Women Clergy - 1996-2001 (Box 67)
    - Women's Perspective Book Group: 1 of 2 - 1966-2007 (Box 67)
    - Women's Perspective Book Group: 2 of 2 - 1974-2002 (Box 67)
    - 'Her Voice, Our Voice': Women's Solstice - 1986 (Box 50)
    - Women and Spirituality - 1987 (Box 50)
    - Inclusive Language - ca. 1990 (Box 52)
    - Confronting the Holocaust: A Mandate for the 21st Century - 1996 (Box 66)
    - Women in the Church Movement - 1983-1987 (Box 54)
    - Fall Meeting 1992 Correspondence: San Francisco - 1992 (Box 56)
    - Hennepin Avenue UMC - 2000-2009 (Box 57)
    - RMN Address Lists - 2000-2001 (Box 58)
    - GCCUIC Project - 2001-2006 (Box 59)
    - UMC/Late 20th Century - 1980-2008 (Box 59)
    - Reconciling Board - 1995-2002 (Box 63)
    - OLOC: Mpls Chapter - 2000-2002 (Box 97)
    - PSR: Center for GL in Religion Ministry - 1998-2007 (Box 97)
    - US: 2 Classes - 1969-1970 (Box 97)
    - Princeton/Boston - 1957-2008 (Box 97)
    - Garrett Conflicts (Race, Gifting, Resignation) - 1996-2003 (Box 97)
    - [Untitled] - 1994-2003 (Box 98)
    - Garrett ETS: BIOS - 1989-1991 (Box 98)
    - Citizen's Scholarship Fund - 2000 (Box 98)
- Personal Files, 1924-2011 and undated
  This series contains materials documenting Powers' personal life, relationships, and history. This includes personal correspondence, diaries, clippings, calendars, and notes.
  - JA Powers Personal Correspondence - 1969-1996 (8 folders) (Box 68)
  - JAP Schedules - 1977-1996 (Box 69)
  - Mankato, Minnesota - Undated (Box 68)
  - Travel - Undated (Box 69)
  - JA Powers' Trip to India - 1978 (Box 69)
  - Travel: Japan - 1979-1981 (Box 70)
  - Russia Trip - 1999 (Box 70)
  - South Africa Trip - 1997 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence - 1983-1988 (Box 70)
  - Personal Papers and Correspondence - 1981-1988 (Box 70)
  - JAP/Savings/Articles: Personal - 1975-1995 (Box 70)
  - JAP: Correspondence, Commendations, Complaints - 1980s (Box 70)
  - Falling in Love - 1941-1987 (Box 70)
  - Judy Berglund - 1964-1983 (Box 70)
  - J.A.P. - 1971 or 1972 (Box 70)
  - Marge JA Troubled Times - 1978-1981 (Box 70)
  - Mayer Personal - 1970-1983 (Box 71)
  - Pride - 1987-1988 (Box 71)
  - Marge: 88+ (1/3) - 1982-1992 (Box 71)
  - Marge: 88+ (2/3) - 1982-2009 (Box 71)
  - Marge: 88+ (3/3) - 1989-1991 (Box 72)
  - Mayer, Marge - 1982-2010 (Box 72)
  - Ingram, Beryl - 1985-2007 (Box 72)
  - Valerie Ford - 1977-1992 (Box 72)
  - Valerie's Poems Articles (Some Letters) - 1981-1985 (Box 72)
  - B - Undated (Box 73)
  - Ford, Val - 1982-2010 (Box 73)
  - Skewes, Ruth - 1976-1982 (Box 73)
  - JAP's Heritage - 1921-2003 (Box 73)
  - Childhood: Plus - 1936-2009 (Box 74)
  - Documents - 1947-1977 (Box 74)
  - Mankato H.S. Homecoming - 1950-2005 (Box 74)
  - Struggling w/ Sexuality: High School-College - 1924-1951 (Box 74)
  - Mankato State U./Truman Wood - 1991-2002 (Box 74)
  - Centenary Church: Mankato - Undated (Box 74)
  - Danforth - 2008 (Box 74)
  - Wallace - 1969-1983 (Box 74)
  - Danny Grads - 2000-2011 (Box 74)
  - Danny Grads - 1955-1960 (Box 74)
  - Danny Grads Reunion - 1993 (Box 74)
  - Family of Origin - 1943-2010 (Box 75)
  - Mankato High School - 1949-1995 (Box 75)
  - Mankato/College - 1951-1954 (Box 75)
  - Appreciations - 1979-2009 (Box 76)
  - Mastectomy Correspondence - 1994-2001 (Box 76)
  - JA Powers Birthdays - 1982-2010 (Box 76)
  - 60th Birthday - 1992 (Box 76)
  - Body, Mind, Spirit - 1995-2010 (Box 76)
  - Condolences After Breakup With Marge - 1988-2001 (Box 77)
  - Condolences After Breakup With Marge from JA Powers' Support Circle - 1987-1990 (Box 77)
  - Personal Therapy Journal - 1983-1984 (Box 77)
  - Struggling With Loss - 1988 (Box 77)
  - Struggling With Sexuality Post College - 1970-1988 (Box 77)
  - Correspondence: Personal - 1950s-1999 (4 folders) (Box 77)
  - JA Powers Correspondence/Personal Reflections (Newsletters) - 1954-2010 (Box 77)
  - JA Powers Correspondence, Reflection - 1995-2010 (Box 78)
  - Personal Notes - 1958-1996 (Box 78)
  - Hobbies - 1990-2006 (Box 78)
  - Misc Photos (Incudes JA Powers Annual Portraits) - 1970-2011 (Box 79)
  - Misc Correspondence - 1993-2010 (Box 79)
  - Ruth: Adams Murray - 1964-1973 (Box 79)
  - Elizabeth Andrew - 1996-2009 (Box 79)
  - Blons, Susan - 1992 (Box 79)
  - John Elizabeth Cole - 1960-2010 (Box 79)
  - Sister Corita/JA Powers: Correspondence: Articles: Motive Magazines - 1964-1972 (Box 79)
  - Eck, Diana - 1998 (Box 79)
  - Steve Fink: Funeral/Memorial Service/Letters to from Friends - 1987-1993 (Box 79)
  - James Holsinger/Larry Pickens - 2007-2008 (Box 79)
  - Hubert Humphrey - 1978 (Box 79)
  - Hubert Humphrey Newspapers - 1978 (Box 79)
  - Huston, Robert - 2010 (Box 80)
  - JA Powers Family of Choice: Ginny/John Kruse - 1978-2005 (Box 80)
  - Lynn Larson (and Others) - 1965-2010 (Box 80)
  - Lawson, Jim Phil - 1958-2000 (Box 80)
  - Jan Love - 1991-2006 (Box 80)
  - Manbeck, Deane Connie: 60th Birthday - 1998-2009 (Box 80)
  - Sisterly Conversations (VA Mollencott) - 1991-1996 (Box 80)
  - Phil Paris - 1973-1986 (Box 80)
  - Steve's Writings - 1972-1988 (Box 80)
  - Jane Cary Peck - 1989-1992 (Box 81)
  - Randolph, Harland - 1954 (Box 81)
  - Bruce Carol Robbins - 2003-2009 (Box 81)
  - Self, Nan - 1976-1986 (Box 81)
  - Stanovsky, Elaine - 1987-1991 (Box 81)
  - Tanner, Mary - 2001-2009 (Box 81)
  - Weidman, Judy - 1999-2001 (Box 81)
  - Others - 1990-2008 (Box 81)
  - Calendars - 1995-2010 (Box 81)
  - Diaries - 1995 (Box 81)
  - Memorial Services: Family Friends - 1960s-1980s (Box 81)
  - Obituaries - 1989-2007 (Box 81)
  - Jeanne Audrey Powers estate information - 1999 (Box 81)
  - JA Powers Gift Proposal to Seminaries - 1995-2001 (Box 81)
  - Contributions - 1982, 1984, 1991, 1993-2001 (Box 81)
  - GETS Struggle re Proposed Financial Gift - 1992-2000 (Box 72)
  - Material From JAP's Mother's Scrapbook About JAP - 1957-1974 (Box 80)
  - JA Powers Correspondence to Family (saved by her mother) - Undated (Box 82)
  - Jeanne Audrey Powers Correspondence, Family - Undated (Box 82)
  - Condolences after deaths in family - Undated (Box 82)
  - Personal Correspondence (Cards) - Undated (Box 83)
  - Abels, Paul and Bishops - 1977-1978 (Box 78)
  - Bryant, Anita - 1977 (Box 78)
  - Jimmy Creech Resulting Actions - 1994-2001 (Box 78)
  - Creed (Doug) Survey - 2001 (Box 78)
  - Delong, Amy - 2011 (Box 78)
  - Greg Dell Resulting Actions - 1998-2000 (Box 78)
  - Huskey, Rick - 1975-1977 (Box 78)
  - Wheatley, Mel - 1982 (Box 78)
  - Jeanne Audrey Powers - 1960-1977 (Box 78)
- Printed Materials, 1970-2004 and undated
  - Books and Theses
    - Woman's Song - 1986 (Box 86)
    - Women Church Celebrations: Feminist Liturgies for the Lenten Season - 1985 (Box 86)
    - Let All The People Praise Thee: Components for Inclusive Worship - 1978 (Box 86)
    - Soul Journeys: Images of the Feminine God - 1987 (Box 86)
    - Feminist Liturgies: Claiming Ourselves Church - 1981 (Box 86)
    - The Lima Liturgy Revisited: An Ecumenical Liturgy of Solidarity - 1990 (Box 86)
    - Resources for Sections: The Theme, Subthemes, and Issues - 1991 (Box 86)
    - According to the Scriptures: A World YWCA World Council of Churches Publication - Undated (Box 86)
    - The Letter of Paul to the ROMANS - Undated (Box 86)
    - Leap in Faith - 1971 (Box 86)
    - Middle East Panel Report: A Study Document: National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA - 1980 (Box 86)
    - Dr. Diedre Kriewald - ca. 1985 (Box 86)
    - Forging Solidarity Links - December 1985 (Box 87)
    - More Hymnal - 1989 (Box 87)
    - Book of Worship Committee - 1988-1992 (Box 87)
    - The People's Story - ca. 1970 (Box 87)
    - "Risk" Book (UMC Information Project) - 2000-2004 (Box 87)
    - English (Reflection): 9-11 Papers - 2001-2002 (Box 87)
    - Children's Literature - 1993 (Box 87)
    - Children's Literature, Katherine Peterson - 1978-1992 (Box 87)
    - Poems - Undated (Box 87)
  - Pamphlets, Articles, and Clippings
    - In God's Image - April 1986 (Box 83)
    - Journal of Sacred Feminine Wisdom - 1995 (Box 83)
    - In God's Image - Spring 1995 (Box 83)
    - In God's Image - Summer 1995 (Box 83)
    - In God's Image - Winter 1993 (Box 83)